pace.com 2016-11-29

# Privacy Policy | Pace

## **About this Policy**

Your privacy is important to us. We have created this Privacy Policy to explain what personal information we collect when you visit our website at [www.pace.com](http://www.pace.com/) (“ **Website** ”).  This Policy also explains the purposes for which we may use that personal information. "Personal information" is information that can identify you or another person and which relates to you or that other person.

**Important: Please note that this Privacy Policy forms part of ourTerms of Use.  You should read this Privacy Policy very carefully.  By submitting personal information to us, you consent to our collection and use of that information as explained in this Privacy Policy.**

## **Who are we?**

We are Pace Limited (formerly Pace plc). “Pace” is a trading name and is a registered trademark of Pace Limited, a company registered in England under company number 1672847. Our registered office is at Victoria Road, Saltaire, West Yorkshire, BD18 3LF.

We are required to comply with the Data Protection Act 1998 (“ **DPA** ”) in relation to the personal information we hold about you.  Under the DPA, Pace Limited is known as a data controller in respect of the personal information which we collect from you using this Website and to which this Privacy Policy applies. This means that when you provide personal information to us, we have certain responsibilities in relation to that personal information.  Pace Limited has notified the Office of the Information Commissioner of its data processing activities: our registration number is Z5989422.

## **What information do we collect from visitors to the Website and how is it used?**

We may collect personal information from visitors to our Website in different ways.  For example, you may complete one of our online enquiry forms, e-mail an enquiry to us using one of the links which we provide on our Website or you may complete our online registration form to subscribe to our e-mail alerts. 

The exact nature of the personal information which we collect from you will depend on your enquiry.  However, the information we collect will in most cases, include your contact details such as your title, name, company (if relevant) and email address.  In addition, you may also need to provide us with more specific information depending on the nature of your enquiry.  For example, if you would like to subscribe to our news alerts then you will need to provide us with information about the topics you are interested in so that we send appropriate alerts.

If you wish to raise a more general enquiry or have a particular topic which is of interest to you, then you will need to give us sufficient information in order for us to deal with it. Similarly, you might also send information by completing one of our comments fields such as if you complete our Website feedback form or use the technical enquiry form to raise questions. In each case, the additional information which you provide may also contain personal information which will also be treated in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

The information which you provide will be held on our records and used for the proper administration of our business and to deal with the enquiries or requests which you make.  We may also use the information from time to time, for our market research purposes.

We also provide information on our Website on the careers pages about our current vacancies and invite people who are interested in a vacancy at Pace, to complete our online application forms.  Similarly, you may send us your CV on a speculative basis by completing our speculative application form.  We will use the information you provide to consider your application and may also retain your details on our records so that we can consider your details for future positions.  Where you raise a speculative enquiry, you will be required to confirm that you agree to Pace retaining your details for that purpose.

Note also that some of the information which you provide may include what is known as sensitive personal data, such as information about trade union memberships, religious belief or health. Please note that by sending this information to us, you specifically consent to our using that information for the purposes outlined in this Policy _._

## **Other uses of your personal information: Marketing and sharing data**

As well as dealing with your enquiries, we may use your personal information to provide you with marketing information such as details of our promotions, new services and changes to the Website. We will do this in accordance with the marketing preferences which you tell us about on the relevant web pages.

If you decide at any time that you do not wish to receive marketing information, please email us at **[info@pace.com](mailto:info@pace.com "Email us")** with details of your request.  Please note that it may take a short time for us to remove your details from our marketing list so the change may not be made immediately.

Please note that when using your personal information in accordance with this Policy, it may be that we need to make your details available to other members of the Pace group of companies in order to deal with your enquiry.  Please note however that we will not share personal information about you with third parties outside the Pace group except strictly if we have a legitimate need, such as if we are under a legal obligation to do so or as explained in this Policy from time to time.

We do not trade or rent your personal information to third parties.

## **When you submit information to us – your obligations**

When you provide any personal information to us, you warrant that it is accurate and up to date. This is very important because if you provide details which are inaccurate then we may not be able to deal with your enquiry. You should therefore check that all details are accurate and without error.

You should inform us if any information which we hold about you requires updating.  If you would like us to update any personal details which we hold about, then please write to us at Pace Limited, Victoria Road, Saltaire, BD18 3LF, providing details of the change.

If you submit a third party's details to us for any reason, for example, if you wish us to respond to your enquiry by contacting another person, if you raise an enquiry on someone else’s behalf or if you would like someone else to receive our email alerts, you must first have obtained their permission to do so. By providing details about someone else, you confirm that you have all appropriate permissions.  

## **How do you access the personal information we hold about you?**

To obtain a copy of the personal information we hold about you, please write to the Company Secretary at Pace Limited, Victoria Road, Saltaire, BD18 3LF, enclosing a cheque or postal order for £10 made payable to Pace Limited to cover our administration costs. As soon as we are satisfied as to your identity we will send you, within 40 days of receipt of your written request and the fee, a copy of all the personal information we hold about you which we are legally required to disclose to you.

## **Use of Cookies  
**

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site.

The table below explains the cookies we use and why.

**Cookie**|  **Name**|  **Purpose**|  **More Information**  
---|---|---|---  
  
Essential site cookie

| 

ASP.NET_SessionId  
(First party cookie)

| 

To remember your selections or preferences that you’ve already made during your current visit to the Pace site.

| 

Set upon your arrival to the Pace site.

Expires when you exit your browser.

Stores a randomly generated twenty character string that uniquely identifies your browser session, for the duration of your current visit to the Pace site.

For further information see [How and why session IDs are reused in ASP.NET](http://support.microsoft.com/kb/899918)  
  
Essential site cookie

| 

RegionCookie  
(First party cookie)

| 

To remember your region preference made during your first visit to the Pace site.

| 

Set upon your first arrival to the Pace site.

Expires never.

Stores either ‘global’ or ‘americas’ that identifies your region preference to the Pace site.

Your region preference is set by either: 

1\. Automatically using your browsers IP address block to associate a region.   
2\. Requesting you to select a region.  
  
Essential site cookie

| 

privacy_cookie  
(First party cookie)

| 

To remember that you have been shown the cookie policy pop-up

| 

Set upon your first arrival to the Pace site.

Expires in 365 days.  
  
Google Analytics

| 

_utma  
_utmb  
_utmc  
_utmz  
(First party cookies)

| 

To collect information about how visitors use the Pace site.

We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.

| 

Set upon your first arrival to the Pace site.

_utma expires after two years  
_utmb expires after thirty minutes  
_utmc expires when you exit the browser  
_utmz expires after six month

Stores a randomly generated number that uniquely identifies your browser session, for the duration of your visit to the Pace site and for each of your visits to the Pace site.

For further information see [Google Analytics Overview and Privacy Policy](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html).  
  
AddThis

| 

di   
dt   
loc   
psc   
ssh   
sshs   
uid   
uit   
(Third party cookies for domain .addthis.com)

| 

To integrate the Pace site with third party social media sites.

AddThis gives end users a simple and easy way to share content across the social web, and provides publishers with increased web traffic and in-depth analytics.

| 

Set upon your first arrival to any Pace site page that has the “Bookmark & Share” feature.

di expires after two years   
dt expires after one month   
loc expires after three months   
psc expires after two years  
ssh expires after two years  
sshs expires after two years  
uid expires after two years  
uit expires after one day

For further information see [AddThis Privacy & Data Practices](http://www.addthis.com/privacy).

Selecting one of the “Bookmark & Share” links will open a page to a social media site that may use additional cookies.  
  
Hemscott IR

| 

JSESSIONID   
_utma   
_utmb   
_utmc   
_utmz   
(Third party cookies for domain .hemscottir.com)

| 

To display up to date Pace share price information for the “Investors” area of the Pace site.

| 

Set upon your first arrival to the Pace site page “Investors > Share Price”.

JSESSIONID expires when you exit the browser.   
_utma expires after two years  
_utmb expires after thirty minutes  
_utmc expires when you exit the browser  
_utmz expires after six months  
  
Most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

## **What about third party websites that you can access via our Website**

The Website contains links to our other Pace website at [www.pace.com/americas](http://www.pace.com/americas).The information which is provided to us using those websites is also covered by this Privacy Policy.

However, our Website also contains links to third party websites which are outside our control and which are not covered by this Privacy Policy. Links to those websites are provided for your convenience only. If you access other websites using the links provided, the operators of those websites may collect personal information from you, which may be used in accordance with any privacy policies which they may provide. We recommend that you read any such privacy policies on third party websites. We are not liable for the practices of such third party website operators in respect of your personal information and any information which you submit shall be a matter solely for you to determine.  

## **Security of your data**

We will take all reasonable steps to keep personal information about you secure in accordance with the requirements of the Data Protection Act 1998. The Internet is global and no data transmitted via the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure during transmission. We cannot warrant the security of any information you transmit to us before we receive it.

It is also possible that the information you provide to us will be temporarily transferred via a route outside the European Economic Area (" **EEA** ") as it passes between you and us.  Further, it may be that in order to deal with your enquiry or request, we need to transfer your personal information outside the EEA, for example, if you apply for a job in one of our worldwide locationsor if you raise a general or technical enquiry which may be dealt with by one of our members of staff based overseas. By providing your personal information to us, you consent to our using your data in this way and specifically, to it being transferred outside the EEA.

Please note that in accordance with our security procedures we may also request proof of your identity before disclosing certain information to you.

## **How will you know if we make any changes to this Privacy Policy?**

We may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make any substantial changes to the way in which we use your personal information, we will notify you by posting a notice on the Website's homepage. You can view the current version of our Privacy Policy at any time by clicking on the Privacy Policy link on the Pace Corporate homepage or via the link at the bottom of each page.

## EU Safe Harbor Privacy Policy

The following link states the EU Safe Harbor Privacy Policy for Pace.  http://www.pace.com/universal/privacy-policy/eusafe-harbor/
